sdge.com 2017-03-24

# Website Privacy Policy | San Diego Gas & Electric

Para la versión en español

Please also see our [Privacy Notice](https://www.sdge.com/customer-privacy/privacy-notices) regarding the privacy of your energy usage information. 

San Diego Gas and Electric Company (“SDG&E”) is committed to keeping our visitors informed about how we use the information we gather on our web site, at our mobile optimized web site, and in our mobile apps (collectively, the “web site”).  By using our web site or obtaining any product or service through our web site, you agree to the collection and use of information as set forth in this policy.  If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use the web site.

Please be aware that other sites accessible through SDG&E’s web site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use, and disclosure practices.  The information practices of those other sites linked to SDG&E’s web site are not covered by this privacy policy.

## I. Information We Collect and How We Use It

In order to better provide you with products and services, SDG&E’s web site collects two types of information: Personal Information and Non Personal Information. 

**Personal Information:** “Personal Information” refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are and can be used to identify, contact, or locate you.  You may choose not to provide any Personal Information and you will still be able to access most portions of the web site.  However, Personal Information may be collected from visitors seeking to obtain services offered by SDG&E on this web site, such as:

  * Enrollment in and use of My Account;
  * Applications regarding possible employment;
  * Enrollment in CARE or other customer assistance programs;
  * Use of SDG&E’s mobile apps;
  * Applications for energy efficiency program participation, rebates, and incentives; and
  * Requesting to be included on mailing, email, texting, landline telephone, or cellular telephone lists of SDG&E, as may be described in more detail on this web site from time to time.  Additionally, online communications relating to utility services may also require follow-up contacts (such as emails, texts, and telephone "call backs") and responses regarding the services to be utilized - including billings and payments.

Examples of Personal Information you may submit include your name or, when combined with your name or other information which could reasonably be used to identify you, your mailing address, telephone number, mobile phone number, email address, and other identification and contact information.  We may also collect certain financial account information (if you choose to provide it), as well as other types of information that you may have entered into employment applications.  In the event that you apply to the CARE program, you may also be requested to disclose your enrollment in other governmental programs (such as food stamps/SNAP, Supplemental Security Income, and the National School Lunch Program).

SDG&E uses this Personal Information to provide services, conduct its business, and improve our visitors’ experience on our web site.

**Non Personal Information:** “Non Personal Information” refers to information that does not identify a specific individual by itself or in combination with other Non Personal Information.  SDG&E may collect Non Personal Information by using cookies, agents, or through the collection of traffic data and location information.

**Do Not Track** : At this time, our web site does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals sent from your web browser.  Additionally, we use a variety of third-party services to help provide our services and to help us understand the use of our web site.  These third-party service providers may collect information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, even if you have enabled your browser’s DNT functionality.

**Cookies:** SDG&E’s web site may store cookies on your computer or other device to allow us to monitor your use of the web site.   No attempts are made to identify individual users unless actions are taken to identify yourself by an “opt in,” for example:

  * Individual services are requested;
  * Application is made regarding possible employment;
  * Inclusion on a SDG&E mailing list is requested;
  * Illegal behavior or unauthorized activities are suspected; or
  * User identification is required under law.

Cookies are used to improve the usefulness of our web site for our visitors.

**Agents:** We may also work with 3rd party service providers or solutions which employ “agents” to monitor, track, and analyze user behavior and traffic data on their device and on this web site.  The information collected by the agents may include, without limitation: hardware model, unique device identifiers (UDID), mobile network information including phone number, the agent version, platform, SDK version, timestamp, API key (identifier for application), application version, model, manufacturer and OS version of device or hardware, session start/stop time, locale, time zone, and network status (WiFi, etc.).  Information collected through the agents is used to customize services and improve web site usability.  Information collected through agents may identify individual users in combination with previously provided Personal Information.

**Traffic Data:**  SDG&E automatically collects and maintains statistical information from our web site’s data logs that concern web site activity, navigation, network traffic flow, and volume (“Traffic Data”).  Examples of Traffic Data include the following:

  * Name of the domain, or URL, from which the visitor accesses the Internet (e.g., "a company.com"; "a school.edu"; or "an agency.gov");
  * Internet Protocol (“IP”) Number;
  * Type of web browser used;
  * Web pages visited; and
  * Date and time this web site is visited.

Our primary purpose for collecting Traffic Data is to optimize the usefulness to visitors of our web site.    Traffic Data is also helpful in permitting us to improve the overall user experience on our web site.  Traffic Data may identify individual visitors in combination with previously provided Personal Information.

**Location Information:** Certain location-enabled functionality (e.g., locating the nearest SDG&E payment office or nearest CNG station) made available in SDG&E’s web site is provided by third party providers.  Your use of that functionality is subject to such third party’s terms and conditions and privacy policy (as updated from time to time). When you use such location-enabled services, SDG&E may also receive information about your actual location, like GPS signals sent by a mobile device or via your IP address. Location-enabled services may also use various technologies to determine location, such as sensor data from your device that may, for example, provide information on nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers.  Location information helps SDG&E customize and tailor services to you.  Location information may identify individual users in combination with previously provided Personal Information.

## II. Sharing Your Information with Third Parties

SDG&E will not, without your consent, share your Personal Information with third parties for their commercial purposes except that SDG&E may share your Personal Information with third-parties, including certain affiliated companies (consistent with applicable laws and regulations) or other trusted businesses solely in order to enable them to perform services for SDG&E related to SDG&E’s own business purposes (subject to confidentiality and security obligations).

**Compliance with Laws and Public Safety:** SDG&E may also disclose Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us or to protect or defend the rights, property, or safety of our users, others, or ourselves.  SDG&E may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personal Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personal Information upon receipt of a court order or subpoena or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation.  SDG&E fully cooperates with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities.  SDG&E reserves the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

**Mergers and Acquisitions:** In the event of a merger, consolidation, reorganization, or sale or transfer of all or substantially all of the assets or business of SDG&E, one of the assets that would generally be transferred is the information we collect from our visitors and customers (including both Personal Information and Non Personal Information). However, the use of this information by any successor entity would still be governed by the terms of this policy, as amended from time to time, including any amendment after such transaction.

## III. Information Security Practices

SDG&E uses commercially reasonable efforts to prevent third parties from acquiring, altering, or destroying information made available to SDG&E through this web site.  These efforts include monitoring network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information and under some circumstances encrypting sensitive information using Secure Socket Layers (“SSL”) or other comparable technology.  Monitoring also occurs to prevent any activity that is illegal, or which may subject SDG&E to legal liability or damage.  SDG&E is committed to maintaining the web site’s security and its ongoing compliance with law so that this service will remain available to all visitors.

Although SDG&E takes commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized third parties from acquiring Personal Information submitted to SDG&E on this web site, an unlawful interception or acquisition by a third party may still be possible.

## IV. Children

SDG&E does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13 years of age. Additionally, we are not aware of any content on our web site that would be considered harmful to children.  If SDG&E learns that we have inadvertently gathered Personal Information from children under 13, we will erase such information from our records and terminate the applicable account.

## V. Links

This web site may provide links to various governmental, industry association and other third party web sites or materials. These links are provided for informational purposes only.  SDG&E does not endorse any advice, goods or services offered by third parties. To the extent third party materials contain assertions of fact, recommendations, or any other interpretations or advice, the third party is solely responsible for the content of the third party site, and SDG&E makes no representation as to the accuracy, completeness or fitness for any purpose or use thereof.  Further, SDG&E has not verified the privacy policies applicable to third party web sites or hosted materials, or determined what actions such parties will take regarding the privacy of visitors.  Accordingly, you should carefully review the privacy policies of any third party sites accessible from any SDG&E web site.  In no event shall SDG&E be responsible for any third party content, policies or actions. SDG&E encourages you to ask questions and to be very cautious before you disclose your Personal Information to third parties.

## VI. Choices Regarding Marketing Correspondence

**Promotional Emails:** You will have the choice to opt out of receiving promotional emails for products and/or services offered by SDG&E. Once we have processed your request, we will stop sending you, within the legally required timeframes, non-transactional promotional emails with respect to products and/or services offered by us unless you opt back in to receiving such communications.  You can opt out of receiving non-transactional promotional emails from us either (a) by following the unsubscribe instructions in the applicable email you receive from us (if applicable), (b) while you are completing our online web form (if applicable), or (c) by calling us at (800) 411-7343.

**Our Operational Emails:** Despite your choices regarding non-transactional promotional emails, we may continue to send you operational emails for non-promotional or transactional purposes, including, without limitation: billing, conservation, outage management, and safety.

## VII. Changes to This Privacy Policy

(last updated February 5, 2016)

SDG&E reserves the right, at any time, and without notice, to add to, change, modify, or update this Privacy Policy by posting a revised policy on this web site.  Any revised Privacy Policy shall be effective immediately on posting.  However, any time this policy is updated, the date of modification will be posted.

## VIII. Disclaimer

SDG&E is not responsible in the event that any password provided to a user is obtained by a third party or for any unlawful activities in connection with this web site.  In the event a user believes any password has been obtained without permission by third parties, or if the visitor has other privacy concerns, the user should contact SDG&E immediately so the password can be changed, or other steps taken as appropriate. This notification should be made to [info@sdge.com](mailto:info@sdge.com?Subject=SDGE%20Privacy).

## IX .Questions or Comments

If you have any questions or comments regarding (a) our web site Privacy Policy, or (b) any other questions about this web site, SDG&E or its services, please contact SDG&E by e-mail at [info@sdge.com](mailto:info@sdge.com?Subject=SDGE%20Privacy), or by phone at (800) 411-SDGE, or by regular mail at 8330 Century Park Court, San Diego, CA 92123-1538.

Please note, however, that information regarding these contacts or correspondence with SDG&E may be retained in a file that is specific to you.

## Other Languages

  * Armenian
